Parker Satterfield

E: parkers205@gmail.com

C: 205-515-6771

GitHub: parkersatterfield

Summary

I am currently seeking a role as a Software Engineer. After graduating from Auburn University in 2019 with a degree in Biological Systems Engineering, I worked as an engineering consultant in Atlanta for two years before moving back home to Birmingham. In November of 2020, I started a company, Dibs Funding, with the goal of connecting the startup community in a way that provided both entertainment and fundraising tools. Though I have known how to program since I was in high school, my experience building Dibs is where I was first introduced to the world of web development. I developed the MVP for Dibs and found a new passion for designing web apps. While working on my startup, I enrolled in Georgia Tech's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, and I am now seeking a full-time position as an engineer for a company in my hometown of Birmingham. I am 25 years old, career-driven, hard-working, and have an entrepreneurial spirit.

Education

Georgia Tech Bootcamps 2021

Full Stack Web Development

Auburn University 2015-2019

Bachelors of Biosystems Engineering Minor in Business

Skills

- UI/UX design and wireframing
- TDD specifically using Jest
- API creation and routing for multi-page and single-page apps
- Improving SEO and accessibility
- Working proficiency with Microsoft Office suite
- Working proficiency in a team environment with version control tools such as Git and GitHub
- Technical writing

Technologies

- MERN Stack
- GraphQL
- Popular JavaScript libraries such as React, jQuery, Moment.js, etc.
- Node.js and popular npm packages such as bcrypt, express, and express-handlebars.
- Basic web development languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6)
- Popular CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Materialize
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud service platforms: *Heroku, Netlify, Github Pages*

Work History

Freelance Web Developer 2021-Present

Using UpWork to meet clients, I completed frontend design and web development projects for my clients

Founder, Dibs Funding 2021-Present

Founded and created a social networking and fundraising web app to provide early stage startups with a platform to blog, receive feedback, and raise money to fund the upfront costs of starting their company

Project Engineer, Keck & Wood, Inc. 2019-2021

Worked on various infrastructure projects including water treatment plant design, roadway design, flood management, and city planning

Research Assistant, Auburn University 2018-2019

Worked under Dr. Lauren Beckingham to write a Matlab program that used machine learning to identify minerality in a 3D CT image from a 2D training image

Projects



DibsStartup project built, Bubble.io



Portfolio My portfolio site, React



Reloc8
Bootcamp
project, Yelp
API



Sibs
UpWork project,
PReact, design

References

References available upon request. Thank you!